(
"ai_sub_version": "3.5.2",
"generated_at": "2026-08-17T18:27:03.551799",
"lyrics_prompt_version": 9,
"subtitles_prompt_version": 18,
"complete": true,
"max_retries_exceeded": false,
"any_pending": false,
"settings": (
"ai": (
"model": null,
"model_subtitles": "google-gla:gemini-3.5-flash-lite",
"model_lyrics": "google-gla:gemini-3.5-flash-lite",
"rpm": 4,
"tpm": 250000,
"google": (
"file_cache_ttl": 10,
"use_files_api": true,
"max_storage_gb": 18.0
),
"search": (
"qps": 0.3,
"max_length": 4096,
"web_search_tool": "langsearch",
"timeout": 60.0,
"retries": 3,
"min_wait_seconds": 1.0,
"max_wait_seconds": 10.0,
"multiplier": 2.0
),
"validation_buffer_ms": 2000,
"verification_gap_seconds": 60,
"gap_verification_retries": 1,
"gap_verification_ignore_start": true,
"gap_verification_ignore_end": true
),
"split": (
"max_seconds": 300,
"re_encode": (
"enabled": false,
"fps": 1.0,
"height": 360,
"bitrate_kb": 35,
"threshold_mb": 20,
"duration_tolerance_ms": 100,
"encoder": null
),
"start_offset_min": 0
"thread": (
"uploads": 4,
"re_encode": 2,
"lyrics": 4,
"subtitles": 4
),
"retry": (
"per_run": 5,
"max_runs": 3,
"multiplier": 2.0,
"min_wait_seconds": 30.0,
"max_wait_seconds": 300
),
"log": (
"level": "info",
"timestamps": true,
"scrub": false,
"progress_bars": true,
"progress_bar_width": 80,
"progress_bar_refresh_seconds": 1.0
)
みんな！24時間、マジ達成！
Everyone! We really achieved 24 hours!
だけど、だけど、だけど…
But, but, but...
まだ終われないよね？心残りも見て、
It's not over yet, right? Look at all the unfinished business—
ぺこーら24スペシャルライブ、残ってるのよー！
There's still the Pekora 24 Special Live left!
皆さんのおかげでここまで来れて、
Thanks to everyone, I've made it this far,
そしてぜひね、ちょっと感謝も、たくさんたくさん返したいので、やっぱアイドルぺこですから、
and I definitely want to express my gratitude many times over, because I'm idol Pekora,
お歌で返していけたらなと思っております。
so I hope to return it through my songs.
そしてゲストさんもたくさんいますのでお楽しみに！
And there will be lots of guests too, so look forward to it!
そして5年目もよろしくお願いいたします！
And please continue to support us in our 5th year!
そしたら早速、
So without further ado,
1曲目から入っていけたらなと思います。
I'd like to jump right into the first song.
聞いてください！
Please listen!
まわるまわるふたりのフィーリング
Revolving, revolving, our feelings
空回ってる空回ってるハート君のせいだよ
Spinning out, spinning out, my heart—it's your fault
ラブのやり取りじゃ足りない
Exchanging love just isn't enough
キミにふわふわしている
I'm floating on air around you
恋愛脳！
Love-addled brain!
なんか重々で辛い 今回もこんなんだ
Somehow heavy and painful, it's like this again
このセリフじゃ生ぬるい 毎回こんなんだ
This line is too lukewarm, it's like this every time
はっと脳髄がラン 毎回来るこんなんだ
Suddenly my brain runs wild, happening over and over
そう、それは罠 キミと目が合った
Yes, that's a trap, our eyes met
ちょっと待ってほしいって 醸す愛情に
Asking you to wait a second, to the love you exude
どうにかして振り向いて
Somehow make you turn around
ワンツーシスイては現れない この気持ちの重量はしよう
One, two, three—it doesn't show, let's measure the weight of this feeling
は、べきわーどは分かってんだけど言えない
Ha, the keyword is clear, but I can't say it
まだ曖昧にしたい
I still want to keep it ambiguous
まわるまわるふたりのフィーリング
Revolving, revolving, our feelings
空回ってる空回ってるハート君のせいだよ
Spinning out, spinning out, my heart—it's your fault
ちょっとやってらんない！じゃまだ足りない
I can't take this anymore! Still not enough
キミにファンテージしたい 愛のユウマブテ
I want to fantasize about you, the illusion of love
こればまだなんて言ってもほら
No matter what people say, look
だって表面じゃまだ 本当は十度の
Because on the surface, it's actually ten degrees
ちょっとものみって 醸す愛情に
Asking you to look for a second, to the love you exude
どうにかして振り向いて
Somehow make you turn around
ワンツーシスイては現れない この気持ちの重量はしよう
One, two, three—it doesn't show, let's measure the weight of this feeling
は、べきわーどは分かってんだけど言えない
Ha, the keyword is clear, but I can't say it
まだ曖昧にしたい
I still want to keep it ambiguous
まわるまわるふたりのフィーリング
Revolving, revolving, our feelings
空回ってる空回ってるハート君のせいだよ
Spinning out, spinning out, my heart—it's your fault
ラブのやり取りじゃ足りない
Exchanging love just isn't enough
キミにふわふわしている
I'm floating on air around you
もっとアピールして もうハートのバイバイげ
Appeal more, my heart is saying bye-bye
エビデンスもっと持って この気持ちをごーどーじょーして
Bring more evidence, sympathize with this feeling
なんて言っちゃったら 怖ぁ無難を見してんだから
If I say things like that, you're hiding your true self
そんなの絶対許しません キミだけこそが許せません
I will never forgive that, only you are unforgivable
デレデレなんかないないよ 気づいたならすぐまいまいよ
There's no acting all mushy, if you noticed, come right to me
独り占めしたいひとりきりでいたい
I want to hog you, I want to be alone with you
そんなのちっとも思わないよ 嘘っていうのは嘘っていうのは
I don't think that at all—when I say it's a lie, when I say it's a lie
嘘でどうしたらいいの こんがらがっててらくだなんて
How should I handle these lies? Getting tangled up...
本当はだって分かってるよ ユーエムすらおぼつかないほど
Because I actually know, to the point where even my name slips
キミとの境界溶かしたい 過去死まで溺って
I want to melt the boundary with you, drowning to the point of past death
ままで押したい押したい
I want to push and push just like this
このキューアイホノからで回る
Revolving right from this Q.I. spark
あたしのフィーリング 今だっての回ってるハート
My feelings, my heart is revolving right now
かなり痛いけど駄目なとこまで駄目押ししたい
It hurts quite a bit, but I want to push my luck to the max
見つめ合って恋をして
Looking at each other and falling in love,
無我夢中で追いかけて
chasing after it in a trance,
だけどもっと知りたくて メラメラしてる
but wanting to know more, it's blazing up.
願うほど謎が増え
The more I wish, the more mysteries grow;
想うほど熱になる だからもっと飛び込むの 未開の世界
the more I feel, the hotter it gets.
恋とか夢とか誰でも信じるけれど
Everyone believes in things like love and dreams,
そこそこ攻めなきゃつまらないよ
but if you don't push your limits, it's boring.
ギリギリ愛 いけないボーダーライン
Borderline of desperate love,
難易度Gでも 全て壊してみせる
even at difficulty G, I'll break it all down.
キリカブ舞 さらなるGへと
Dancing wildly into even greater G's,
意識が溶ける 体は制御不能
my consciousness melts, my body out of control.
イッちまうかもね
I might just lose it.
無敵の笑顔で荒らすメディア
Stirring up the media with an invincible smile,
知りたいその秘密ミステリアス
that mysterious secret everyone wants to know.
抜け出しているとこさえ彼女のエリア
Even her unguarded moments are part of her territory.
完璧で嘘つきな君は
Perfect and full of lies, you are
天才的なアイドル様
a genius idol-sama!
今日何食べた? 好きな本は?
What did you eat today? What book do you like?
遊びに行くならどこに行くの?
Where do you go when you go out to play?
何も食べてない それは内緒
Haven't eaten anything—that's a secret.
何をきかれてものらりくらり
Evading whatever you're asked with a smile.
淡々と思いながら 燦々とか
Thinking calmly, shining brightly,
見えそうで見えない秘密は蜜の味
secrets almost seen are the sweetest honey.
あれもないないない これもないないない
There's none of this, none of that either.
好きなタイプは? 相手は? さあ答えて
What's your type? Who's the partner? Come on, answer!
「誰かを好きになることなんて私分からないからさ」
"I don't even know what it's like to love someone,"
嘘か本当か知り得ないそんな言葉にまた一人堕ちる
falling for words where truth and lies blur.
誰もが目を奪われていく
Everyone has their eyes stolen away,
君は完璧で究極のアイドル
you are the perfect, ultimate idol.
金輪際現れない
An existence like you will never
一番星の生まれ変わり
appear again, the reincarnation of the morning star.
ああ、その笑顔で愛してるで 誰もかも虜にしていく
Ah, captivating everyone with that smiling "I love you,"
その瞳が その言葉が
those eyes, those words—
嘘でもそれは完全なアイ
even if a lie, it's complete love.
はいはいあの子は特別です
Yeah, yeah, that girl is special.
我々はハナからおまけです
We're just useless extras from the start.
お星様の引き立て役Bです
We're supporting role B to the star.
全てがあの子のお陰なわけない
It can't be thanks to her for everything!
洒落臭い 嫉妬なんてないわけがない
How annoying, of course there's jealousy.
これはネタじゃない からこそ許せない
This isn't a joke, that's why I can't forgive it.
完璧じゃない 君じゃ許せない
If you're not perfect, I won't forgive you.
自分を許せない 誰よりも強い 君以外は認めない
I won't forgive myself; I accept no one stronger than you!
誰もが信じ崇めてる まさに最強で無敵のアイドル
Everyone worships and believes in her, truly the strongest, invincible idol.
弱点なんて見せちゃダメ 知りたいことだけ見せずに
Don't ever show your weaknesses, hide what people want to know,
唯一無二じゃなくちゃ イヤイヤ
you have to be one and only, no no!
それこそ本物の愛
That right there is true love.
得意の笑顔で沸かすメディア
Stirring up the media with your signature smile,
隠し切るこの秘密だけは
keeping this secret completely hidden away—
愛してるって嘘で積むキャリア
building a career on the lie of "I love you."
これこそ私なりの愛だ
This right here is my own kind of love.
流れる汗も綺麗なアクア
Even the sweat flowing down is a clear aqua,
ルビーを隠したこの瞼
hiding ruby under these eyelids.
歌い踊り私はマリア
Singing and dancing, I am Maria,
そう嘘はとびきりの愛だ
yes, lies are the ultimate love.
誰かに愛されたことも 誰かのこと愛したこともない
I've never been loved by anyone, nor have I ever loved anyone.
そんな私の嘘がいつか本当になること 信じている
I believe that someday these lies of mine will become the truth.
いつかきっと全部手に入れる 私はそう欲張りなアイドル
Someday I'll surely get my hands on everything, yes, I'm a greedy idol.
等身大でみんなのこと ちゃんと愛したいから
Because I want to genuinely love everyone as I truly am,
今日も嘘をつくの この言葉がいつか本当に日を願って
today too I tell lies, wishing for the day these words finally become real.
それでもやっぱ君と君にだけは言えずにいたけど
Even so, to you and you alone, I couldn't say it—
ああやっと言えた これは絶対嘘じゃない愛してる
Ah, I finally said it. This is definitely no lie: I love you.
みんなあ！まずは恋愛の、そしてアイドルの2曲を歌わせてもらったペコ！
Everyone! First, I sang two songs: Renai Circulation and Idol!
どうペコ？ちゃんと歌えて踊れてましたペコ？
How was it? Did I sing and dance well, Peko?
そしてみんなのお楽しみゲストパート！このあとすぐペコ！
And now, everyone's favorite guest part! Right after this, Peko!
てなわけでペコーらは行ってくるね！バイバーイ！
With that said, Pekora's heading out! Bye-bye!
電波テンポアップして
Turn up the radio tempo,
絶賛感電中！
and get totally electrified!
あなたにも忘れたいこと
Are there things you'd want to forget, too?
かなしいこと あるのかしらね
Sad things, I wonder if there are any?
知らない映画なのに涙をながすのは
Shedding tears at a movie you don't even know,
ドラマチックが足りていないからよ
must mean you're lacking drama.
そんな愚にも付かないことくだらないこと考えてばかりね
Thinking about such stupid and pointless things...
雨が上がれば愛もその横顔も誰かのものになるのでしょう
When the rain clears up, love and that profile will belong to someone else.
嘘っぱちのファンデーションも全部今夜のためなのに一体全体如し何故何故一体何故っての
All those fake foundations are for tonight, but why on earth, why?
一体全体如し何故何故一体何故っての
Tell me why you've gone and left it all behind!
不安定なカンテラ何処まで行くの
This unstable lantern, just how far will it go?
あなた一切合切引っ剥がしてもわあ冗談じゃないわよ
I'm not joking, you know!
トウキョウ・シャンディ・ランデヴ
Tokyo Shandy Rendezvous,
その時が来たって何にもなんないぜ
even if that time comes, it won't change a thing.
曖昧な本当なんてメランコリ化するだけ
Vague truths just turn into melancholy,
あたしをさあ掠らって今テイクオンミー
so snatch me away now, take on me!
ちゃんちゃらおかしな法度ばかで食指がびくともしないわ
There are so many weird rules that my appetite won't budge.
実態の無い感情放っておいて策になんてありゃあせんのに何故
Emotions with no substance are just left behind, strategy?
ああもう懲り懲りよあたしの喝となる気質もじっと堪えて取り繕って
Ah, I've had enough of this punishment!
とはととと臨界点
Reaching the boiling point, it's a critical moment.
年がら年中リップサービス鈍感かましては辟易
Lip service year-round, insensitive bashing is commonplace.
どんがらがっしゃんフィールガールは涙の目にも鬼
A feel-girl is a devil even with teary eyes.
今や頭の中のミュージックのせいであなたの話は一向に聞き取れないし
Now, with the music in my head, I can't hear a word you say.
少しはまとなこと言ってよ
Please say something serious!
回り出すターンテーブルねえ全部忘れさせてよ
The turntable starts to spin, hey, let me forget everything.
だけど一体全体如し何故何故一体何故っての不安定なカンテラ消えないままで
The unstable lantern won't go out.
あなた一口両舌食い違ってもわあ冗談じゃないわよ
Even if that time comes, it won't change a thing.
トウキョウ・シャンディ・ランデヴ
Tokyo Shandy Rendezvous,
その時が来たって何にもなんないぜ
even if that time comes, it won't change a thing.
曖昧な本当なんてメランコリ化するだけ
Vague truths just turn into melancholy.
あたしをさあ掠らって今テイクオンミー
Snatch me away now, take on me!
冗談じゃないわよトウキョウ・シャンディ・ランデヴ
I'm not joking, it's Tokyo Shandy Rendezvous!
その時が来たって何にもなんないぜ
Even if that time comes, it won't change a thing.
冗談じゃないわ感情なんてランドリーで落とすだけ
Emotions are just washed away in the laundry.
あたしと確かめ合ってイエローマジック
Confirm it with me, yellow magic!
トウキョウ・シャンディ・ランデヴ
Tokyo Shandy Rendezvous,
その時が来たって何にもなんないぜ
even if that time comes, it won't change a thing.
曖昧な本当なんてメランコリ化するだけ
Vague truths just turn into melancholy,
あたしをさあ掠らって今テイクオンミー
so snatch me away now, take on me!
そう簡単な祈りだった
It was a simple prayer,
端から段々と消える歎息今から
fading away piece by piece from the start.
緞帳が上がるから静かな会場を後にさよなら
The curtain rises, leaving behind a quiet venue. Sayonara.
言いかけていた事が一つ消えてまた増えて背中に後ろめたさが残る
What I wanted to say keeps disappearing and reappearing, leaving a lingering regret behind.
従いたい心根を吐き出さぬように込めて
Locking away the obedient feelings so they won't spill out,
胸の中が澱のように濁る
the inside of my chest grows murky like silt.
受け止めたいことが自分さえ抱えられず持て余したそれを守っている
I couldn't even embrace what I wanted to accept, and I'm protecting what I couldn't hold onto.
霞んだ声はからからに喉を焼いて埋め尽くす
A muffled voice burns and fills my parched throat.
何を言うべきか分からなくて感じてたものが遠く放たれていた
Not knowing what to say, what I felt was cast far away.
同じようで違うなんだかいつまで行こうか何処まで行けるのか
Looking the same yet different, just how far can I go and how far can I reach?
定かじゃないなら何を想うの
If it's uncertain, what should I think?
僕らが離れるなら僕らが迷うならその度に何回も繋がれるように
If we're going to drift apart, if we're going to get lost, so we can reconnect each time,
ここに居てくれるなら離さずにいられたら
if you'll stay here, I won't let you go,
まだ誰も知らない感覚で救われていく
and we'll be saved by a feeling nobody knows yet.
平穏とは消耗を以て代わりに成す
Peace is replaced with exhaustion,
実際はどうか変わりはなく
Though in truth nothing really changes.
享楽とは嘘で成る
Pleasure is built upon lies,
綻ぶ前 どこを出ていこうか
Before it unravels, where shall we head out?
と都合の良い願いを 同じように同じように呟く
Muttering such convenient wishes, just the same, just the same.
何処から聞こうか 何を見失うか
Where shall I ask from? What will I lose sight of?
定かじゃないから此処を動けない
Nothing is certain, so I can't move from here.
僕らが疲れるなら これ以上無いなら
If we grow tired, if there's nothing more than this,
その度に何回も逃げ出せる様に 心が守れる様に 奪われない様に
So I can escape time and time again, so my heart can be protected, so it won't be stolen away,
互いに託して身体を預けてよ
Let's entrust ourselves to each other and surrender our bodies.
君と泣き 君と笑い 君と怒り
Crying with you, laughing with you, getting angry with you,
君と歌い 君と踊り 君と話し
Singing with you, dancing with you, talking with you.
何時まで続くんだろうと
Wondering how long this will last,
同じように同じように呟く
Muttering just the same, just the same.
いま忘れないよう 刻まれた空気を
So as not to forget, the air branded into me,
これから何度 思い出すのだろう
How many times will I remember it from now on?
僕らが離れるなら 僕らが迷うなら その度に何回も繋がれる様に ここに居てくれるなら 離さず居られたら
If we drift apart, if we get lost, so we can reconnect time and time again, if you stay here with me, if we can stay together without parting,
まだ誰も知らない 感覚で僕の 生きているすべてを 確かめて正しくして
With a sensation no one else knows yet, verifying and making right everything about my life.
サンドリヨン 作詞:orange 作曲:Dios/シグナルP
[Song: Cendrillon / Lyrics: orange / Music: Dios / Signal-P]
朝まで踊る夢だけ見せて 時計の解く魔法
Show me only the dream of dancing until morning, the magic undone by the clock's chime.
曖昧な指 誘う階段 三段飛ばしに跳ねていく
Ambiguous fingers beckon up the stairs, bounding up three steps at a time.
馬車の中で震えてた みすぼらしい古着 廻り巡る夜の舞踏
Shivering inside the carriage in shabby old clothes, spinning round and round at the night's masked ball.
墓所の中で 震えてた 身を縮めてた
Trembling within the graveyard, shrinking into myself.
見知らぬ顔探す 鬨の声響く
Searching for unfamiliar faces, the battle cries echo.
密やかな顔 探す 囁くあの声が
Searching for a quiet face, that whispering voice,
握り締めた刃突き立てて すべてを奪えと
Thrusting forward a clenched blade, telling me to take everything.
皆殺しの 後ろ 笑みが見え隠れして
Behind the slaughter, a smile flickers in view.
偽りの慈しみにさえ 触れつつむセラフィム
Even false affection enfolds us like a seraphim.
今更帰る 震えているの あなたが目をやする時計
Returning now, trembling at the clock where you cast your eyes.
剥ぎ取り踊る スロープ抜けて 喉まで伸びる指の先で
Stripping off and dancing, slipping past the slope, at the very tips of fingers reaching up to the throat.
救う蜘蛛糸 絡む衝動 背骨抜け出していく刹那
Rescuing spider silk, entangling impulses, the moment my spine slips out.
今さら吠える 震えているの あなたが目をやる時計
Howling now, trembling at the clock where you cast your eyes.
靴脱ぎ踊る 角をぶつけて 喉まで伸びる指の点で
Removing my shoes and dancing, hitting the corner, at the point of fingers reaching up to the throat.
すくう蜘蛛糸 絡みつけて 走る鼓動で背骨抜けいく切な
Entangling the rescuing spider silk, with racing heartbeats my spine slips out in anguish.
鐘は鳴らさないで あなたに膝まずき
Do not ring the bell, kneeling before you,
まだダメと叫んだ右手蹟突き刺す サヨナラ
My right hand screaming "not yet," thrusting forward a farewell.
わっちゅーげっちゅー熱烈オンチュー
What'chu get chu, passionate on-chuu!
しゅきしゅぎて弾けたビビッドマインド
A vivid mind bursting from loving you too much!
ルーレットグッドスタートきっとゲット
Roulette, good start, we'll surely get it!
1度！1度！1度！
Once! Once! Once!
永久センキューときめきノックユー
Eternal thank you, heart-throbbing knock you!
1ミリの隙間にダイビング
Diving into a 1-millimeter gap!
ラブスタンプ全部コンプしてアップ
Collecting all love stamps and leveling up!
いいぞ！いいぞ！いいぞ！いいぞ！
Great! Great! Great! Great!
せーの！
Ready, set!
いまも耳に あなたの吐息が
Even now, your sigh echoes in my ears,
月ささやきの遠い夢
A distant dream whispered by the moon.
すれ違うごし光る月が
The moonlight passing by us,
キミにかぶせたベール
Is a veil draped over you.
ドメス膝で咲いて
Blooming on domestic knees,
ティーアラわ投げ捨てて
Throwing away the tiara,
見つめ合う瞳と瞳が火花を放つ
Gazing eyes meet and send sparks flying.
孤独な魂が炎を上げ光り合う
Lonely souls blaze and shine together.
その涙すくえないなら まるでひとり
If I can't catch those tears, I'm all alone.
あの時よまれ今はあなたに酔いしれて
Back then, stop time, now I'm intoxicated by you,
揺れる鼓動一つ一つを刻みつけてたい
Wanting to engrave every single throbbing beat.
この生まれ熱く濡れ打ち付けるたかわりに
Burning and getting wet with this birth, in return for pounding,
これ以上は動けないよ まるで手放せる
I can't move anymore, as if letting go.
わっちゅーげっちゅー熱烈オンチュー
What'chu get chu, passionate on-chuu!
しゅきしゅぎて弾けたビビッドマインド
A vivid mind bursting from loving you too much!
ルーレットグッドスタートきっとゲット
Roulette, good start, we'll surely get it!
1度！1度！1度！
Once! Once! Once!
永久センキューときめきノックユー
Eternal thank you, heart-throbbing knock you!
1ミリの隙間にダイビング
Diving into a 1-millimeter gap!
ラブスタンプ全部コンプしてアップ
Collecting all love stamps and leveling up!
いいぞ！いいぞ！いいぞ！いいぞ！
Great! Great! Great! Great!
せーの！
Ready, set!
だって今日はゴッドメンタル
Because today is a god-tier mental!
いっそましきチャレンジャー
A dashing challenger,
ちょっとだけセンチメンタル
Just a little bit sentimental!
だいしきゅーだいしきょー 1.2.3.はい！
Daishikyu daishuki, 1, 2, 3, go!
まみむめもめもめもみれないの
Mamimumemo memo memo, I can't look!
立ちつてとてとてとてが触れて
Tachitsuteto teto teto, our hands touch,
だいしきゅーだいしきゅーニンあんれ！
Daishikyu daishuki, nin are!
もっときゆきゆきゆきゆきゅーと強制ラブ！
More kiyu kiyu kiyu kiyu, forced love!
あのねくりおね透けてるハート
Hey, you know, Creone's transparent heart,
でもねこの胸見つかさないで
But hey, don't let anyone see this chest!
だいしきゅーだいしきゅーニンあんれ！
Daishikyu daishuki, nin are!
アタシじゃないなんて終わってんね
Saying it's not me is so over!
わっちゅーげっちゅー密月オンチュー
What'chu get chu, honeymoon on-chuu!
しゅきしゅぎて空振るキューティマインド
A cute mind swinging and missing from loving you too much!
ルーレットちょっとストップ一端急停止
Roulette, stop for a sec, sudden full stop!
いや！いや！いや！でも！
No! No! No! But!
せーの！
Ready, set!
だって今日は求めている
Because today I'm longing for you,
うるわしきチャレンジャー
A gorgeous challenger!
ハート描いたオートメーション
Automation drawing hearts,
だいしきゅーだいしきゅー 1.2.3.はい！
Daishikyu daishuki, 1, 2, 3, go!
まみむめもろもろろにしてほしいの
Mamimumemo roro roro, I want you to make it all muddled!
なにぬねこねこ恋のコネクト
Nani nuneko neko, connection of love!
だいしきゅーだいしきゅーニンあんれ！
Daishikyu daishuki, nin are!
もっときつきつきつきつきっしゅ強制ラブ！
More kitsu kitsu kitsu kitsu, forced love!
あのねまりおね操られレディー
Hey, you know, Marionette, a manipulated lady,
でもねそれもね悪くはないね
But hey, even that's not so bad!
だいしきゅーだいしきゅーニンあんれ！
Daishikyu daishuki, nin are!
アタシじゃないなんて終わってんね
Saying it's not me is so over!
フレンドリーなフリして
Acting all friendly,
周波数を乱さないで
Don't disrupt the frequency!
いわくつきの魅惑のリップ
Enchanting lips with a dark history,
リアルになる be love
Becoming real, be love!
まみむめもめもめもみれないの
Mamimumemo memo memo, I can't look!
立ちつてとてとてとてが触れて
Tachitsuteto teto teto, our hands touch,
すきすぎてくらり やみつきちゅうちゅうくらり
I love you so much, I'm dizzy, addicted, smooch, I'm dizzy.
アタシじゃないなんて
Saying it's not me...
終わってんねー！
That's totally over!
まみむめも、めも、めも、見れないの
Mamimumemo, memo, memo, I can't even look
手つづけて、て、て、て手が触れて
Hands touching over and over again
だいしきゅーだいしゅきになれ！
Become totally head over heels in love!
もっとぎゅぎゅぎゅぎゅぎゅっさきょうせーらぶ！
Give me more hugs, forced love!
あのねクリオネおめつけてるハート
You know, that Kurione-eyed heart
でもねこの胸見つかさナイで
But hey, don't peek into this heart of mine
だいしきゅーだいしゅきになれ！
Become totally head over heels in love!
アタシじゃないなんて終わってんねー！
Saying it's not me is totally over!
Yeah yeah yeah...
向かい風の中で 嘆いているよりも
Rather than sighing against the headwind,
上手く行く事を想像すれば
If you imagine things going well,
いつの日か変わる時がくる
The day will eventually come when things change.
夢中で生きていたら 何気ないことで
If you live engrossed in the moment, over trivial things,
愛が傷ついて ためらいながら何度も立ち上がるよ
love gets hurt, hesitating yet standing up over and over again.
思い出の後先を 考えたら寂しすぎるね
Thinking about the before and after of memories is too lonely,
騒がしい未来が向こうで きっと待ってるから
Because a bustling future is surely waiting ahead.
走り出せ 走り出せ 明日を迎えに行こう
Run, run, let's go welcome tomorrow!
君だけの音を聞かせてよ 全部感じているよ
Let me hear your unique sound, I'm feeling all of it.
止めないで 止めないで 今を動かす気持ち
Don't stop, don't stop the feeling that moves the present,
どんなに小さなつぼみでも 一つだけの Happiness
No matter how small the bud, it's one and only Happiness.
思い出の後先を 考えたら寂しすぎるね
Thinking about the before and after of memories is too lonely,
騒がしい未来が向こうで きっと待ってるから
Because a bustling future is surely waiting ahead.
走り出せ 走り出せ 明日を迎えに行こう
Run, run, let's go welcome tomorrow!
君だけの音を聞かせてよ 全部感じているよ
Let me hear your unique sound, I'm feeling all of it.
走り出せ 走り出せ 明日を迎えに行こう
Run, run, let's go welcome tomorrow!
君だけの音を聞かせてよ 全部感じているよ
Let me hear your unique sound, I'm feeling all of it.
止めないで 止めないで 今を動かす気持ち
Don't stop, don't stop the feeling that moves the present,
どんなに小さなつぼみでも 一つだけの Happiness
No matter how small the bud, it's one and only Happiness.
涙の気持ちさえ 言葉に出来ない
Even the feeling of tears cannot be put into words,
幸せの虹は 何色なんて気にしなくていいから
And you don't need to worry about what color the rainbow of happiness is.
答えを見つけようと 思い出また積み重ねて
Trying to find the answer, we pile up memories once more,
ここから新しい場所へ 何も恐れないで
From here to a new place, without fearing anything.
遠くまで 遠くまで どこまでも続く道
Far away, far away, a road that continues anywhere,
君だけの声を聞かせてよ ずっとそばにいるよ
Let me hear your voice alone, I'll always be by your side.
止めないで 止めないで ずっと信じる気持ち
Don't stop, don't stop the feeling of always believing,
今は名もないつぼみだけれど 一つだけの Happiness
It's just a nameless bud right now, but it's one and only Happiness.
幸せの虹は 何色なんて気にしなくていいから
You don't need to worry about what color the rainbow of happiness is.
答えを見つけようと 思い出また積み重ねて
Trying to find the answer, we pile up memories once more,
ここから新しい場所へ 何も恐れないで
From here to a new place, without fearing anything.
遠くまで 遠くまで どこまでも続く道
Far away, far away, a road that continues anywhere,
君だけの声を聞かせてよ ずっとそばにいるよ
Let me hear your voice alone, I'll always be by your side.
止めないで 止めないで ずっと信じる気持ち
Don't stop, don't stop the feeling of always believing,
遠くまで 遠くまで どこまでも続く道
Far away, far away, a road that continues anywhere,
君だけの声を聞かせてよ ずっとそばにいるよ
Let me hear your voice alone, I'll always be by your side.
止めないで 止めないで ずっと信じる気持ち
Don't stop, don't stop the feeling of always believing,
今は名もないつぼみだけれど 一つだけの Happiness
It's just a nameless bud right now, but it's one and only Happiness.
走り出せ 走り出せ 明日を迎えに行こう
Run, run, let's go welcome tomorrow!
君だけの音を聞かせてよ 全部感じているよ
Let me hear your unique sound, I'm feeling all of it.
止めないで 止めないで 今を動かす気持ち
Don't stop, don't stop the feeling that moves the present,
どんなに小さなつぼみでも 一つだけの Happiness
No matter how small the bud, it's one and only Happiness.
走り出せ 走り出せ 明日を迎えに行こう
Run, run, let's go welcome tomorrow!
君だけの音を聞かせてよ 全部感じているよ
Let me hear your unique sound, I'm feeling all of it.
止めないで 止めないで 今を動かす気持ち
Don't stop, don't stop the feeling that moves the present,
どんなに小さなつぼみでも 一つだけの Happiness
No matter how small the bud, it's one and only Happiness.
走り出せ 走り出せ 明日を迎えに行こう
Run, run, let's go welcome tomorrow!
君だけの音を聞かせてよ 全部感じているよ
Let me hear your unique sound, I'm feeling all of it.
止めないで 止めないで 今を動かす気持ち
Don't stop, don't stop the feeling that moves the present,
どんなに小さなつぼみでも 一つだけの Happiness
No matter how small the bud, it's one and only Happiness.
いえ、いえ、いえ、いえ！
Yeah, yeah, yeah, yeah!
Happiness!
みんな、みんな、まだ、まだ！
Everyone, everyone! Hold on!
まだ、待ってね、ぺこだよ！
Hold on a second, Pekora!
ちょっとここから、ぺこからのお知らせタイム！
I have an announcement to make!
いまも多分気づいてる人もいるとは思いますぺこですけども、ま、ぺこらも4周年となったので、
Well, I'm sure some of you have already noticed, right? Pekora's 4th anniversary is here, so...
今回も出ますよ！4周年記念グッズ紹介していきたいと思いますと思うぺこです！
we're releasing goods for it again this year! Presenting the 4th Anniversary Commemorative Full Set!
さぁぺこら活動4周年記念グッズのこちらでございます！
So, let's go over the 4th anniversary commemorative goods!
1つ目は、こちら！
First is this...
ラバーマット！こちらになんと、はぐれママ描き下ろしのラバーマットとなっております！うさぎぺこらのいろんな衣装が書いてあってかわいいぺこですよね！
The Rubber Mat! Featuring an illustration by Hagure-mama of Pekora in various outfits!
ぜひ使ってください、ぺこぺこらと一緒に大安吉日してもらえたらなと思うぺこ！そして続いては、こちら！
Please use it and spend time together with Pekora! And next is...
どどん！さきひろ先生描き下ろしの、アクリルスタンド！いえい！
This! An acrylic stand featuring an illustration by Hilo-sensei!
今までさ、ぺこら多分だけど、まぁ公式とかのアクリルとかはあったけど、新3Dのね、衣装のアクリルスタンドは初めて出すぺこですので、今回が初ぺこですよ！しかも、
Now, Pekora has had official acrylic stands and things before, but this is our first-ever 3D outfit acrylic stand! And on top of that...
普通のアクリルスタンドじゃない、ホログラム加工付きのキラキラしたね、アクリルスタンドぺこですので、ぜひお部屋に1個置いてもいいのかなと思いますので、よろしくお願いしますぺこー！
It's not just a regular acrylic stand—it features a holographic finish! So you should definitely display one in your room!
続いては、こちら！
And next is...
タンブラー！やっぱさ、配信には飲み物！みんなのお供に一つタンブラー必要ぺこかなと思いまして、ぜひね、このかわいいタンブラーを持ってぺこらの配信にこれからも来ていただきたいということで、タンブラー作ってみました！
The Tumbler! You need a drink when you're watching streams, so I thought it'd be great to have a Pekora tumbler to keep you company!
そして最後は、こちら！
And finally...
やっぱ、お部屋に1つは必要、うさだぺこらぬいぐるみ！かわいくないぺこですかー！めちゃめちゃかわいらしく作っていただいております！
This! You definitely need one of these in your room: the Usada Pekora Plushie! Isn't she just super cute?
まあね、結構もうね、ぬいぐるみとかは出てたりもしてるぺこですけど、ぺこらからね、ちゃんと出すのは初めてなので、ぜひたくさんぬいぐるみいっぱいお部屋に飾ってね、一緒にぺこらとともに過ごしてるんだっていう感じで思っていただきたいぺこですので、もう、
Well, we've had plushies before, but this is the first time I'm releasing an official Pekora one! So I really hope you'll get lots of them...
1個とは言わずたくさん一緒にね、ぺこちゃん寝ていただけたらなとも、お部屋にね、飾るだけでもいいぺこだし、あの旅行とかにも連れてってあげたりとか、たくさん使い道があると思いますぺこですので、ぜひお手元によろしくお願いいたしますぺこ！
one is never enough! Get lots so they can keep you company in your room, take them on trips, and find all sorts of ways to enjoy them!
そしてこちらフルセット！
And here is the Full Set!
特典がございます！ちょっとね、数量限定の特典には、
Now, the quantity-limited purchase bonuses include...
ぺこらまた書きます！直筆サイン！そして箱押しの複製メッセージ入り！こちらははぐれ先生の描き下ろしポストカード！そして通常は箱押しの複製サインがあります！
Pekora's handwritten signature, and a postcard with a duplicate message! The regular version comes with duplicate signatures, while the quantity-limited one features a handwritten signature and duplicate message from Hagure-sensei!
そして、このフルセットの特典ボイス！ぺこらの気持ちを伝えたいボイス！なんだんだ、気になるよな、ぺこらが何の気持ちを伝えたいのか、バトルなのか、それとも感謝なのかわからないぺこだけども、聞きたい人はぜひよろしくお願いしますぺこ。ぺこらの思いを詰めたぺこですので、
And this full set also includes a bonus voice track! It's a voice where Pekora shares her true feelings... I wonder what's on her mind? Whether it's a battle cry or just gratitude, I'm not totally sure, but if you want to know what Pekora really thinks and feels, you should definitely pick it up!
本当にね、かわいい4つのね、グッズなので、ぜひともお求めいただけたらなと思うぺこー！
These are four really cute items, so I hope you'll all check them out! Peko!
グッズはこんな感じぺこですかね。
So that's what the goods are like!
そして、本当に4周年、いやもう次から5周年目？5年目か、5年目になるうさだぺこらちょっと4周年はちょっと24時間という今までにない挑戦で、そして最後にはスペシャルライブという、
And really, it's already been 4 years... Wait, is it the 5th year next? Or the 5th anniversary? Pekora's 4th anniversary was 24 hours long, a totally unprecedented challenge, culminating in a special live performance!
いやもう、みんな眠くなってるんじゃないぺこか？大丈夫？もうちょっとあるからね。そして、これからも5年目もね、一緒にぺこらストーリーを歩んでいけたらなと思いますぺこ！
Everyone must have been super sleepy, right? Are you okay? There's still a bit to go! And I hope we can keep walking the Pekora Story together for the 5th year!
そしてこのあとは最後に4周年やって、4年やって、
And finally, we did our 4th anniversary! Four years!
ぺこらにもおりゅすんかね、おりますぺこよねぇ？
Does anyone have "Oryu" for Pekora too? I'm sure there are some, peko, right?
何曲あるか覚えてますか？
Do you remember how many songs there are?
何曲あるか...
How many songs are there...
これからうさだぺこら、おりゅすんめどれーを最後に披露したいなと思います。
From now on, Usada Pekora would like to showcase the "Oryu Medley" at the very end.
最後までみんなちゃんと聴いとけぺこだよ！
Make sure everyone listens carefully right until the end, peko!
それじゃあ準備してきまーす、ばいばーい！
Well then, I'll go get ready, bye-bye!
らんだむぶれいん！わおっ
Random brain! Wow!
叫んじゃえわおっ
Just shout it out, wow!
事件だ 毎日大変
It's an incident, everyday is tough!
大成功のタネだと笑え…泣いちゃうな笑え！
Laugh like it's the seed of success... Don't cry, laugh!
ぺこらった るんるんだった
Pekora was all bouncy and upbeat
ぺこらんだむしちゃいたまえ
Pekora-ndomize if you will!
no no no の指令 無視か yes かうりゃー
No no no, ignore the brain's orders, yes or wryaa!
no no no の指令 ランダムだ random!!
No no no, the brain's orders are random, random!!
no no no の指令 無視か yes かりゃ
No no no, ignore the brain's orders, yes or rya-
受取拒否れぬぞ！
You can't refuse delivery!
なんたいがいなtouch and go
What an outrageous touch-and-go
びゅんとプロペラまわれ
Spin around like a propeller
どこへ向かうかわからない 知らない 知らないんだ
Where are we heading? I don't know, I really don't know!
なんと世界はつながっちゃう
And somehow the world connects
ひょいと越えたら銀河系
Hop across and you're in the galaxy
誰に会いたいって思うんだ？
Who is it you want to meet?
そんなのどうでもいいじゃんいいじゃん 退屈イヤだったらこっち来れば？
Whatever, who cares! If you're bored, why not come over here?
大様な場所なんてさ 自分で作らなくちゃ
Places like that aren't grand, you've got to make them yourself
これぞ説教だ！ どうだこうだどうだこうだ
This is a lecture! How's this, how's that?
有難迷惑か～
A blessing in disguise?
らんだむぶれいん！わおっ
Random brain! Wow!
びっくりだわおっ
Surprising, wow!
生きてりゃ 毎日大変
If you're alive, everyday is tough
大問題の後には 楽しいことあるから
After big problems come fun things
らんだむぶれいん！わおっ
Random brain! Wow!
びっくりだわおっ
Surprising, wow!
生きてりゃ 毎日大変
If you're alive, everyday is tough
大問題の後には 楽しいことあるから
After big problems come fun things
らんだむぶれいん！わおっ
Random brain! Wow!
叫んじゃえわおっ
Just shout it out, wow!
事件だ 毎日大変
It's an incident, everyday is tough!
大成功のタネだと笑え…泣いちゃうな笑え！
Laugh like it's the seed of success... Don't cry, laugh!
ぺこらった るんるんだった
Pekora was all bouncy and upbeat
ぺこらんだむしちゃいたまえ
Pekora-ndomize if you will!
no no no の指令 無視か yes かうりゃー
No no no, ignore the brain's orders, yes or wryaa!
no no no の指令 ランダムだ random!!
No no no, the brain's orders are random, random!!
no no no の指令 無視か yes かりゃ
No no no, ignore the brain's orders, yes or rya-
受取拒否れぬぞ！
You can't refuse delivery!
どっちが好きなのよ！
Which one do you like?!
いいわけバニー
Excuse Bunny!
なんとかできないかな
Isn't there something we can do?
隣のあいつじゃまだな
That guy next door still won't do
先手必勝絶対 童話とは違うな
Strike first, absolute - different from a fairy tale
なんたって競争 苦手だよ そういうの
Competition? I'm bad at that sort of thing
なんだけ寂しい 気持ちは気持ち
Somehow lonely, feelings are feelings
あの娘に負けない 毛羽立ってジェラシー
Not losing to that girl, feathers ruffled with jealousy
言わなきゃって分かっている あでもないこでもない やめにしましょう
I know I have to say it - no, neither, let's stop this
貫け my my my mind 聞きたくない！ いいわけバニー
Pierce through, my my my mind! I don't want to hear it! Excuse Bunny!
団地太no! 優柔不断だんだん
Danchi-ta no! Indecisive step by step
ハニーバニー だりーだりー まじな話
Honey Bunny, boring boring, seriously
どっちが好きなのよ！
Which one do you like?!
よそ見しないで
Don't look away
もう逃げ出したいのは私のほうでしょでしょ？
The one who wants to run away is actually me, right, right?
通しません！反対方向 wanted!
I won't let you pass! Opposite direction, wanted!
いいわけバニー
Excuse Bunny!
大都会は得意？
Are you good with big cities?
興味がねーから超ネガティブ
Zero interest, so super negative
人混み キミ探す 張り紙
Looking for you in the crowd, a flyer
とどけ意気込み！嫉妬はたしなみ
Send my enthusiasm! Jealousy is refinement
荒ぶってポエミー
Wildly poetic
前進あるのみトラブルってエネミー
Only moving forward, trouble is the enemy
疲れちまった一休み
Tired out, take a breather
なんとかねやってよね明日の私
Somehow manage it, tomorrow's me
まかせろ my my my mind
Leave it to my my my mind
決められない！いいわけバニー
Can't decide! Excuse Bunny!
うやむや yes! 唯我独尊そんそん
Ambiguous yes! Sole and supreme
メニーメニーマニーマニー
Many many money money
ガチな話 How much? オトシマエ
Serious talk, how much? Pay the price
旅立とう冒険、そしてインドアの神話へ――
Let's set off on an adventure, and into the indoor myth―
最大級のララララララビット！！
The ultimate Lalalalalabbit!!
最序盤のスライムにびびるのが大概なマイライフ
Getting scared of slime at the very start is basically my life
ワン・ツー・スリーでつながったセカイに愛があふれだす
Love overflows into a world connected by one, two, three
8bitに感じるドキドキ
The 8-bit excitement I feel
2Dのラブじゃだめですか？
Isn't 2D love okay?
運ゲ状態ふざけんなじゃないぞ
Don't screw with me, RNG state isn't a joke
レベルアップして超えてやるあ！
I'll level up and surpass it!
夢に見ているファンファーレの音
The fanfare sound I dream of
乱数調整 一転攻勢
RNG adjustment, turning the tables
一点突破想定外も ロマンの過程――
Point breakthrough, unexpectedness is part of the romance―
ラヴィラヴィちいさなビットにでっかいアイを交信中！
Lavi-lavi, communicating huge love to tiny bits!
ちょっと沼っても許してね？いつだって愛は非効率！
Forgive me if I get a little obsessed? Love is always inefficient!
jumpin' jumpin' 跳ねるハートを捕まえて置いてね！
jumpin' jumpin' Catch my bouncing heart and keep it!
二兎なんて追わないでトルーエンドになるまで
Don't chase two hares until we reach the true end
最大級のララララララビット！！
The ultimate Lalalalalabbit!!
旅立とう 冒険 そして インドアの神話へ――
Let's set off on an adventure, and towards the indoor myth...
最大級の ラララララビット！！
the grandest ra-ra-ra-ra-ra-rabbit!!
うし ね とら うーらーら！ うーらーら！ うーらーら！
Ox, rat, tiger, la-la-la! La-la-la! La-la-la!
全人類 兎化計画！
All humanity bunny-fication plan!
初序盤のスライムに ビビるのが大概なマイライフ
Being scared of slimes at the very beginning is pretty much my life
ワン・トウ・スリーで繋がった セカイに愛があふれだす
Love overflows into a world connected by one, two, three!
8bitに感じるドキドキ 2Dのラブじゃだめですか？
The heart-pounding feeling felt in 8-bit, isn't 2D love okay?
運ゲー状態ふざけんじゃないぞ レベルアップして超えてやるあ！
Don't mess around with RNG! I'll level up and overcome it!
夢に見ているファンファーレの音
The sound of the fanfare I've been dreaming of,
乱数調整 一転攻勢
RNG adjustment, sudden counter-offensive,
一点突破 想定外も ロマンスの過程――
single breakthrough, unexpected events too, the process of romance...
ララララ ラララ
La-ra-ra-ra la-ra-ra,
ラヴィ ラヴィ ちいさなビートで でっかいアイを交信中！
love-it, love-it, communicating huge love with a tiny bit!
ちょっと沼っても許してね？ いつだって愛は非効率！
Forgive me even if I get a bit obsessed, love is always inefficient!
jumpin' jumpin' 飛び跳ねるハートを捕まえておいてね！
Jumpin' jumpin', catch my bounding heart!
二兎なんて追わないで トゥルールエンドになるまで
Don't chase two rabbits until you reach the true ending,
最大級のラララララビット！！
the grandest ra-ra-ra-ra-ra-rabbit!!
らーらら らーらら ぺこーら
Ra-ra-la, ra-ra-la, Pekora!
寂しすぎたら死んじゃう生き物さ
I'm a creature that dies if I get too lonely,
だから一緒にいようね 約束だぺこ！
so let's stay together, it's a promise, peko!
ぴょんぴょんぴょんぴょん ぴょんぴょんぴょんぴょんって未来飛び出せ！
Pyon-pyon-pyon-pyon, jump out into the future!
足元も確かめず跳んだその先で待ってるよ
I'll be waiting where you land without even looking at your feet.
ぴょんぴょんぴょんぴょん ぴょんぴょんぴょんぴょんって思い切りジャンプしたら
Pyon-pyon-pyon-pyon, when you take a big leap,
大気圏も余裕で突破 宇宙の皆様こんにちはー！
you easily break through the atmosphere—hello, everyone in space!
うし ね とら うーらーら！ うーらーら！ うーらーら！
Ox, rat, tiger, la-la-la! La-la-la! La-la-la!
全人類 兎化計画！
All humanity bunny-fication plan!